# **Daniel Letson**

daniel.letson@gmail.com daniel-letson.com 203.470.2639

### Objective

I design digital products with integrity, based on a user-centered research process and 10+ years of experience building both on the web and IRL. I specialize in simple, scalable designs with a keen eye for detail and a knack for non-standard solutions.

### Education

Carnegie Mellon BFA, Industrial Design

> Magna Cum Laude Spring 2008

### Skills

User Experience Design
User Research
Web Accessibility
Data Visualization
Market Research
Information Architecture
UX Writing
Agile Development

Figma Adobe CC Affinity Photo/Designer

> HTML5 / CSS3 JS / ECMAScript Node / NPM ReactJS D3JS Git

## Experience

Fluxx Labs · Senior Product Designer · 2019 - 2024

Directed product design efforts at a leading SaaS platform for nonprofits

- Brought a B2C product from free beta to paid subscription model, achieving profitability within 6 months
- Launched 16 major productivity features to over 30k users at many of the most prominent organizations in US philanthropy
- Built the company's first UI design system, cutting dev time for new features by 20%
- Owned and administered web analytics company-wide
- Mentored a junior designer for 2 years

#### Turnitin · Web Lead, Marketing · 2013 - 2019

Lead design, planning, and development for a global marketing team in Ed-Tech

- Redesigned and developed the company's flagship marketing website, with millions of monthly visitors across 12 regional sites
- Single-handedly built a new global CMS and architected a build/release scheme
- Launched the company's first data-driven marketing campaign and built bespoke data analysis tools for salespeople

#### Klassik Living · Design Contractor · 2010 - 2013

Contractor for an upscale reseller of vintage Danish modern furniture

• Designed and built an online store, including branding, merchandising, and web marketing

#### Zarganis, Inc · Woodworker · 2008 - 2010

Apprentice to a master woodworker

 Designed, engineered, and fabricated custom furniture and architectural elements, including work on a LEED Platinum Certified office suite

#### CREATE Labs · Product Designer · 2007

Intern for an educational robotics program

- · Designed and prototyped interactive robotic devices
- Developed curricula, lead in-person learning events, and conducted user testing workshops

## Volunteering

Internet Archive · Web Developer · 2016

Front-end development and data visualizations for the Political Ad Archive

KALX Berkeley · Music Director · 2014 - 2016

Managed student and community volunteers and liaised with industry representatives on behalf of one of the most venerable radio stations in the country